= kisskh.lv =
♪ From primal chaos to the starry sky ♪
♪ In the whole world, we shall hold the balance ♪
♪ The cauldron tempers divine blades ♪
♪ The furnace refines the empty void ♪
♪ The Way is in mystic fate ♪
♪ Be brave enough to split the primal chaos wide open ♪
[Pull Strings]
[Adapted from the novel by Yan Gui Zheng Zhuan]
Qi Yuan,
watching you tormented
by love sickness day after day
just warms my heart.
Resentment
is the world's best weapon.
This is a drop of Bear Islanders' blood.
Only Bear Islanders' blood
can awaken the Pregenesis Sword.
I want you to use a spell formation
to control someone
and borrow his strength
to turn Bear Islanders' blood to mist.
This jade talisman
was left by Senior Wan.
When the blood mist touches the Pregenesis Sword,
it'll absorb everyone's power.
[Episode 20]
You knew the rumors were about you,
so you hid in Ascendance Sect.
You also knew we were after the Pregenesis Sword,
so this sword
must be hidden on you.
You were careful.
Every move was flawless.
But
that was your biggest weak spot.
Were we a step too late?
My magical power is fading.
This feeling
is just like when we were at Bear Island.
[Hall of Mortal Coils]
Senior.
Why is
my power fading?
Everyone, hold the line!
Wipe out Ascendance Sect!
Charge!
Demon Army,
surround the Hall of Mortal Coils!
Let no one escape!
That's...
Senior,
my power is truly gone!
What do we do?
Monster! Get away!
Get away!
Please?
Get away! Get away!
Xuanya,
you are of noble birth.
If you can,
escape.
I'm a disciple of Ascendance Sect.
I stand with the sect.
Mentor, I'm out of spiritual power.
This...
Their spiritual power is gone.
He...
What to do?
Senior!
All fellow disciples,
draw your swords!
Even if we die today,
we must defend our sect to the last.
Defend our sect to the last!
Senior!
Senior, please wake up.
Senior, wake up. Please.
Senior, look at me.
Wake up.
Senior.
Senior! Senior!
This foolish old man...
It's Bear Islanders' blood.
My mentor was made the formation core.
Bear Islanders' blood woke up the Sword.
I miscalculated.
Little rascal, you
I never saw the formation would drive the Sword.
That was my oversight.
This foolish old man
hid the truth about Kuai Si from me.
But now, I've found the core,
so I can break the formation.
Just give me more time.
Little rascal.
Li Changshou.
Right now,
you don't have to be so rational.
It's okay to cry.
You're human,
not a deity.
No need to control everything.
Don't be afraid.
I'm heading to Ascendance Sect right now.
When I arrive, everything will be fine.
You mustn't!
I ride the clouds.
I'll be there in half a stick of incense's time.
Wait for me.
Yunxiao, don't!
Why?
You're clearly at your wit's end.
I have plenty of strategies.
How could I be at my wit's end?
Don't worry.
You taught me to trust others.
Don't you trust me?
You are
my last resort.
You must not be exposed.
Even if Seizing members are being killed,
I still can't help them?
You've been lying to me.
But I trusted you all this time.
You said you had a plan.
What plan?
Can it save my Seizing fellows?
Let me hear it.
I'm sorry, Yunxiao.
I thought.
I could solve all of this,
repel the Demon Clan
and restore Seizing cultivators.
I thought I could save everyone.
I'm sorry.
If you'd listened to me from the start,
taken the fight to Westdawn Sect,
and even killed Kuai Si first,
things
wouldn't have come to this.
You're always scheming,
yet you keep losing more.
Why is the Great Tribulation drawing near?
I'm heading to Ascendance Sect now.
Yunxiao, you mustn't.
Why?
Because two pieces of the Sword
cannot be in the same place at once.
We only split the Sword fragment into three pieces
to ensure
no one could get this key
and avert the Great Tribulation.
So,
from the moment I got this Sword fragment,
you had already decided
never to see me again?
It's not my decision.
It's fate.
But I have never believed in fate.
Yunxiao,
please, think calmly.
You've been under Westdawn Sect's control.
Did you think they wouldn't anticipate you?
This is a trap.
If you come,
you'll simply become a puppet like my mentor.
What we must do now
isn't how to rescue
those controlled by the Demon Clan,
but how to clear Seizing Sect's name
and restore their innocence.
Yunxiao, please think again.
Alright.
Even now,
you're still thinking of me.
What a selfless hero.
This time, I'll do as you say.
I won't come find you.
But after today, we needn't stay in touch.
I'll follow my own heart from now on.
I won't consult you on every matter.
Farewell,
Li Changshou.
♪ See mortal joys and sorrows ♪
♪ Reunions and partings, as fate unfolds ♪
♪ Alas, love has many twists and turns ♪
♪ Memories filled with sorrow ♪
I'm sorry, Senior.
Senior, you're finally back.
Why can't we use our magical power?
But those demons can.
Because they are from the Demon Clan.
They're immune to the Pregenesis Sword.
What sword?
I must leave here at once.
You're trying to flee now?
They weaken as they get close to me.
Come with me.
Only when the Three Sects join forces
can there be hope.
The Three Sects have to join forces.
The Three Sects have to join forces?
With Ascendance Sect alone,
we can't weather this trial.
Jiu Wu.
Jiu Jiu.
Save Ascendance Sect.
I'm Jiu Wu
at your command.
I'm Jiu Jiu
Fairy Yunxiao, a gifted Seizing disciple.
Why barge into Celestial Court?
Looking for someone.
Looking for someone?
The Celestial Court has its rules.
You can't come and go as you please.
Is that so?
Come in.
Da, Er, I'm starving.
I want some mutton soup.
Hurry, hurry!
Come out, come out!
Are you that great deity?
No.
I'm also from the Sea Deity Sect.
How come I don't recognize you?
Ke Le'er!
That's me.
Quick, quick!
What?
Don't ask.
Come out. Come out now!
Ke Le'er.
So good to see you.
Ke Le'er, Ke Le'er.
Ke Le'er.
You all...
You can leave?
Right.
Then why are you still here?
No one told us to leave.
Yes.
Exactly.
Can we go?
Of course.
You still need to save your people.
Right, go quickly.
Go, go.
Hurry, go, go.
Go now.
Finally, they're gone. Let's go too.
Wait.
We can't take her.
Why?
You belong to the Seizing Sect.
It's dangerous to take you.
You suspect me?
No.
Then what do you mean?
Breaking through means a death battle.
When you see your mentor,
could you strike him?
If she can't do it,
then she's a liability.
Then...
In that case,
I won't go with you.
Your Highness,
the Pearl Elites are well-trained.
Even without magical power, they can fight.
She's from the Seizing Sect.
Without magical power, she's useless.
The Pearl Elites can guard you.
They are your safest choice.
I know that, Si'er.
Thank you for saving me.
But.
I want to protect my senior.
If that is your wish,
then may you shine,
break through the siege,
and survive this trial.
We shall meet again.
Let us go too, Senior.
Wait.
Where is Cansheng?
Cansheng...
Why so many mosquitoes?
Da, Er.
Go, now!
Hurry!
[Subtle and Mystic]
Guard all exits.
Let no one escape.
The Pregenesis Sword must be here.
Changgeng.
How's that? Not bad, right?
I made such a big sacrifice this time.
Senior must be very moved.
Zhao Gongming.
Zhao Gongming, come out!
Zhao.
I've never seen a temple like yours
in Jade Division.
No, just say what you want to say.
Don't touch my money!
Come out and help them.
I'm scared.
My power's faded. I can't win.
Then how did you transform?
My power worked when I transformed.
Now, I lack the power
to change back.
I
5,000 spirit stones.
Go.
Hurry!
Cansheng, what's wrong?
Cansheng.
Go.
Why should I be curious?
Likewise.
I'm done talking to you.
You're a bad man.
I'll go back to the sect and report you.
Changshou.
Senior Yuan Qing scolds sweetly.
It's okay if you move.
It's already late.
I don't care.
Li Changshou!
I must go save Cansheng.
Cansheng's body is special; Don't worry.
Mentor has vanished.
I can't leave Cansheng behind.
Little Uncle,
I treat you like my own brother.
Then Cansheng is my brother too.
I can't just leave him behind.
I must keep him safe,
just as I must keep you safe.
Little Uncle, you go first.
Then I'll bring Cansheng to you.
Thanks for saying you'd protect me.
But I'm Mentor Yuan Ze's first disciple.
He's vanished.
Only I can hold Turtle Island.
♪ At the cloud peak, with sun and moon ♪
I'll bring Cansheng back to see you.
♪ My heart is carved with all living beings ♪
♪ An unexpected meeting in this Primordial World ♪
♪ This lad, at first, is hard to admire ♪
♪ In a flash, I recall our near misses ♪
♪ Fearing inescapable karmic threads ♪
Little Uncle,
I hope I can see you again.
♪ An edge hides, yet flows with ease ♪
♪ Making me lean down and confirm slowly ♪
Cansheng, I'm coming to save you.
Senior!
Senior,
I will protect you.
I will save you!
The Second Prince.
This...
How
can there be a dragon?
Little Uncle.
Little Uncle's clothes.
Who let you in?
This is Turtle Island.
I go where I please.
There are plenty of pitiful people in this world.
If all wallowed in self-pity like you,
they would have died long ago.
You are now one of Turtle Island.
If anyone outside dares to bully you,
I will stand up for you.
You bold demoness!
Don't bully Little Uncle!
I want to protect my senior.
Little Uncle.
Senior, where are you?
I will definitely avenge you.
They didn't catch me.
Don't kill me.
Mentor.
Once I break the formation and get my power back,
we'll be safe again.
Mentor, please hold on.
I've found a way to break it.
But it'll take an incense stick's time.
Chaos Bell.
What bell?
You're not Changgeng.
Who are you?
I have to give my name before I die?
I am Lan Ling'e of Jade Division.
Lan Ling'e?
No.
You are not human.
I am not human.
Right, you're not human.
Then...
We've searched for you for years.
So, you've been here all along.
Looking for me?
You don't know your origins?
I...
What origins?
I have the Pregenesis Sword
- you want.
- Changgeng.
Leave, quickly.
Don't let them catch you.
Thank you so much.
Kill Changgeng! Seize the Sword!
My origins?
What poor quality!
Jerk!
If not for my sister,
5,000 spirit stones would surely not be enough.
Come at me!
Coward!
Coward! Such a coward!
They're all here?
No.
Help!
It's a trap!
You...
You can break the Westdawn secret art?
Li Changshou.
Or perhaps.
I should call you Changgeng.
Everyone, count heads, quickly!
Over here, over here!
Injured, to the Hall of Mortal Coils!
Aunt.
Ling'e.
Junior.
Are you alright?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Where is Senior Changshou?
I can't find him.
Where's Changshou?
Senior Changshou is back at Jade Division.
He's breaking the formation.
That fool.
Off on his own at a time like this?
Where are you heading?
To find Changshou and help him.
You're not going.
Why?
Because you're too restless.
Because you can't stay calm.
Because I'm worried about you!
Didn't I tell you before?
I have an agreement with Qi Yuan.
I promised him
to look after Jade disciples.
I...
A promise must be kept.
This is my duty.
I'll go.
Bye.
Senior, I will go with you.
Stay here.
Why on earth
won't you let me go with you?
You tell me.
Why did I punish you on behalf of Mentor?
Have you forgotten?
Jiu, stay here.
Protect Mentor.
Protect the Hall of Mortal Coils.
That is your duty.
Do you hear me?
Listen to me.
This time, do not let Mentor or me
be disappointed in you.
Take care, Senior.
Stay safe on the road.
That's more like it.
I'm off.
But...
The key to this crisis
is this formation that drains power.
As long as power returns,
the danger will pass.
Then what should we do?
There are two ways.
First, break the formation.
Second,
get rid of the magic instrument driving this formation.
Remember this:
Once safe, find Jiu Jiu
and have her come to me.
Aunt Jiu Jiu?
That's right.
She's our sect's top swords woman.
When magical power is gone,
she's the strongest fighter.
And easiest to fool.
Why say it so bluntly?
I suppose Uncle Jiu Wu is okay?
Sorry, Senior.
It's over.
I botched it.
Changgeng,
keep running.
We finally meet.
What?
Have we not met before?
I've long heard of your name.
Meeting you
is a first for me.
That's good then.
You went through trouble to find me.
Of course.
Because only then
can I kill you.
But more importantly,
it's to let Seizing Sect take the blame
for Ascendance Sect's massacre,
and trigger war among the Three Sects
to turn you against each other.
It's you.
You made the Seizing Sect
shoulder this infamy.
All these years,
you've been West dawn's mole
in Ascendance.
Wrong.
Westdawn didn't make me a mole.
I used Westdawn to strengthen Ascendance.
Strengthen Ascendance?
Westdawn attacked us,
killed many of our disciples,
and took my mentor as the formation core.
That's strengthening Ascendance?
Without destruction, no creation.
Ascendance under Detached Master
is hopeless.
Only I
can lead Ascendance
and dominate the Three Realms.
You're truly hopeless.
So,
you killed Seizing cultivators
and tarnished the sect's name
just to make them
your scapegoats.
Anyway, the Seizing Sect's reputation
is already rotten.
A little more won't matter.
Right.
The Seizing Sect
is despised by all.
This ragtag bunch
consists of misfits and mongrels.
They're heartless.
I'm sick of them.
But they're living beings, aren't they?
They must have feelings.
Then, do you think
they'd grieve over a fellow's death?
What is that to me?
[Steady]
I'll ask you one last time.
Did you lead the Demon Clan here,
use demonic arts on my mentor,
and set up
this power-draining formation?
Not only that.
I also ruined Qi Yuan's foundation,
used Gnatsting Needle
on our fellows,
used Westdawn Sect
for my Aureate Immortal Tribulation,
and expelled all elders
who opposed me.
Elder Kuai.
It was you?
Why isn't it Jiu Jiu?
Junior.
If it were Jiu Jiu,
her sword could've held an incense stick's time.
But Uncle Jiu Wu...
You're buying time.
Elder Kuai,
I never expected
you were behind this plot.
Uncle, buy me some time.
I'll save Mentor first.
Jiu Wu,
though you're Detached Master's disciple,
you've run the sect for years.
I know
you're slick and worldly.
Everyone likes you.
All are willing to heed you.
You're
a real talent.
If you'd follow me,
from now on,
my trust in you
will far surpass that of Detached Master.
Are you willing?
It's too late.
Why do they keep multiplying?
Our sect
has no traitor like you!
What a pity.
Uncle!
I am an Aureate Immortal.
A mere sword cannot harm me.
Changshou, back to the Hall of Mortal Coils!
Uncle, you mustn't!
Now, we're all low on magic arts.
He's not that much stronger.
Is that so?
♪ Once a drifting weed, I loved to roam ♪
♪ Now, a levee holds back the storm ♪
♪ Fight against fate for my life ♪
♪ Close eyes to sense the world ♪
Uncle.
He's using demonic arts now.
We can't beat him.
I'll take you away.
Changshou, listen to me.
I promised your mentor.
I must see it through.
Go!
♪ Though millions block, it echoes loud ♪
Uncle, wait for me.
♪ Plain and unremarkable ♪
♪ From the start, plan for storms ♪
♪ Seek refuge, survive, hide my skill ♪
Two ways to break this formation:
Either break the formation,
or discard the artifact that powers it.
♪ The evil knows no shame ♪
♪ Immortal trials burn cowardice away ♪
♪ The howling wind calls to me ♪
♪ Gouging eyes to light the night and ferry souls ♪
♪ My soul is standing like a mountain ♪
♪ Arrows in flesh as the string ♪
Your Highness.
♪ Standing tall, heart hides its might ♪
♪ Today my name reaches heaven ♪
♪ Actually, I've descended to the world ♪
The golden dragon is your true form.
Once your transformation succeeds,
the Pregenesis Sword won't take effect on you.
I know you wish to save them.
But you don't know how, right?
I wish to save them too.
But you must help me.
♪ Charging against the wind ♪
♪ Old scars reveal the truth ♪
♪ Even if all brave men fall ♪
♪ Chugging the murky wine ♪
♪ Close eyes to sense the world ♪
We've been in the same sect for years.
I really can't bear to kill you.
Knowing you'll lose,
why court your destruction?
♪ From primal chaos ♪
♪ To the starry sky ♪
♪ In the whole world ♪
♪ We shall hold the balance ♪
Junior Qi Yuan,
this time,
you've landed me in deep trouble.
Traitor, face death!
♪ The cauldron tempers divine blades ♪
♪ The furnace refines the empty void ♪
♪ The Way is in mystic fate ♪
Get away.
Thank you for your help.
May I ask your name?
I'm a nameless disciple from Ascendance Sect.
You came on a dragon.
How could you be a nameless disciple?
You are Changgeng?
Changgeng sent me.
He sent you?
Changgeng has a plan to win.
Please come with me.
I am not going.
I have not said where yet.
I am not going anywhere.
It's Seizing vs Human. What's it to me?
You're truly not going?
Absolutely not.
Will you go or not?
What are you doing?
Quick! Pull me up!
Pull me up!
I am warning you.
Will you go or not?
How dare you threaten me?
This is no threat.
It's a request to forces against this crisis.
Joining forces?
What jest is this?
See for yourself.
Those Seizing disciples below
are all bound by demonic arts.
With your Aureate Immortal power,
can't you even see that?
Of course, I can see it.
Today, it's Seizing vs Human.
How about tomorrow?
Elucidating vs Seizing?
Human vs Elucidating?
If this keeps going,
is that your mentor's Way?
You...
A force has now arisen.
They're the Three Sects' common foe.
They want the Three Sects to fight each other.
Must you regret standing idly by
after the enemy bares its fangs?
And Changgeng...
What does Changgeng really want?
He wants to learn to trust.
♪ See mortal joys and sorrows ♪
♪ Reunions and partings, as fate unfolds ♪
♪ Alas, love has many twists and turns ♪
♪ Memories filled with sorrow ♪
♪ Slowly, wishes turn to regret ♪
♪ You've gone afar, like mist fading ♪
♪ Tearfully, this life's bond is not over ♪
♪ Past fragments vanish into night ♪
♪ Down a few more cups of wine ♪
♪ Through land and sea, I ask you to come ♪
♪ For honor's sake, upright and grand ♪
♪ Alas, our story is short ♪
♪ Slowly, wishes turn to regret ♪
♪ You've gone afar, like mist fading ♪
♪ Tears fall, this fate's not done ♪
♪ Past fragments vanish into night ♪